Sonja Parsell

NYC Metro Area | 203-321-9889 | hello@sparsell.com | www.sparsell.com | GitHub| LinkedIn

PROFILE

I'm an organized, detail-oriented and curious software engineer with experience designing and building applications in React (including Redux), JavaScript, Rails and Ruby. I spent 15+ years working in financial services which gave me extensive experience in project management, global collaboration, and team management and building across all financial asset classes. I'm highly resourceful, and relentlessly pursue efficiency and accuracy. I love the details.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Javascript, React, Redux, Ruby, Rails, HTML5, CSS, ActiveRecord, PostgreSQL, SQLite, Git, JSON, RESTful routes, MVC design patterns

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

ClassTech - GITHUB

- An application for parents to show their kids which of their classmates have their own phones.
- Allows users to add a new student and view all students by grade, noting their phone status and any screen time limits they might have. Heavy interest amongst parent groups for this to be live; hosting in progress.
- Designed and built in React with Redux, Rails API and PostgreSQL.

SpendLess - GITHUB

- App to record when a user has spent less; proves how small changes to your spending mindset can save money.
- A user can set a goal, add amounts, and view a cumulative total of how much they have saved, or "spent less".
- Designed and built with JavaScript, Rails API and SQLite.

EXPERIENCE

Leukemia and Lymphoma Society

Volunteer - Salesforce Administrator

New York Metro Area

08/2019 - Present

Maintain patient outreach data and special projects

Whitby School

Greenwich, CT 08/2017 - 08/2019

School Board Member and Fundraising Chair (2016)

• Raised over \$450k at annual gala

New York. NY and London. UK

Barclays Capital *Vice President* - Global Product Control Change Group, Prime Brokerage Controller

08/2008 - 02/2013

- Reduced delivery time by 6 hours for exceptions report by aligning production teams globally
- Transferred daily P/L production to Asia Group
- Mentored and managed rotational analyst cohorts

JPMorgan Chase

New York, NY

Vice President - Structured Notes Controller, Corporate Trust Relationship Manager

03/2003 - 08/2008

- Increased accuracy of revenue allocation by 43% after discovering and correcting mis-mappings; appointed as project lead for division roll-out
- Recovered \$250k from client billing errors after self-initiated analysis and discovery of hard-coded software
- Established revenue share procedure across divisional sales teams and all asset classes

Deutsche Bank

New York, NY and London, UK

Assistant Vice President - Client Relationship Manager - Corporate Trust

02/1998 - 11/2002

- Led project and was primary IT test resource to move manual collateral management system to proprietary software
- Increased client revenue by 18% through excellent client relationships and frequent referrals

EDUCATION

Flatiron School, Remote: Full Stack Web Development - Software Engineering	03/2020 - 11/2021
Pepperdine University, Malibu, CA: BS, Business, BA, French	07/1995
Consensys Academy: Blockchain: Foundations and Use Cases	10/2018
Skillcrush: JavaScript, Responsive Web Design, WordPress, HTML, CSS, Git	09/2018 - Ongoing
Free Code Camp: Responsive Web Design - Certificate, Front End Libraries (in progress)	01/2016 - Ongoing